

Alireza Taheri Tajar

Computer Vision Engineer

M.Sc. graduated in Electrical and Control Engineering and over 4 years' startup founding experience in Intelligent Transportation systems and UAVs. Seeking a new positions related to Artificial Intelligence concepts and fabrication a product in this field.

alirezataheritajar@gmail.com

+98-(936) 856 - 4342

in linkedin.com/in/alireza-taheri

Work Experience

Technical Manager

Sina ATI NET, Hamadan, Iran (www.atisense.ir)

(Sep 2017 – Current)

- * Electronic project
- * Intelligent Transportation System (ITS)
- * Internet of Things
 - **Co-Founder and Technical Manager** Atitek Faradid Pars, Hamedan, Iran (www.atitek.ir)

(Jan 2015 - Sep 2017)

- * Manufacturing of UAVs and services
- * Photogrammetry and Aerial mapping

Education

Master of science

Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran

(Sep 2016 – Sep 2019)

Faculty of Engineering

Department of Control Engineering

M.Sc. Thesis: Counting, Classifying and Detecting the Speed of Passing Vehicles from One Axis based on Image Processing

• Bachelor of science

Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran

(Sep 2012 - Sep 2016)

Faculty of Engineering

Department of Electrical Engineering

B.Sc. Thesis: Designing and fabrication a multirotor drone

Interests

- ★ **Artificial intelligence** (Deep learning based computer vision)
- ★ Intelligent transportation systems (Vehicle detection, Surveillance, Behaviour analysis)
- ★ Internet of Things (Wireless sensors, Smart City)
- **Unmanned Aerial Vehicle** (Photogrammetry)
- **★** Robotics

Accomplished and Academic Projects

- Designing and fabrication **an inductive loop vehicle detector**.
- Designing and fabrication a magnetic sensor vehicle detector.
- Designing and fabrication a multirotor drone for photogrammetry and mapping.
- Designing and fabrication **line follower robot**.

JOURNAL PAPERS

Taheri Tajar, A., Ramazani, A., & mansoorizade, m. (2019). A lightweight Tiny-YOLOv3 vehicle detection algorithm.

(In progress)

Award and Honors Head of Student Entrepreneurship Union, Ministry of Science 2019 and Research 2018 Head of Entrepreneurship Student Committee, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran 2016 Admitted for pursuing graduate studies at Bu-Ali Sina University in fall 2016 without entrance examinations (Only 2016 granted to 10% top students) Member of the Executive Committee of the 14th Alumni 2015 Conference of Festival of Nations Head of Electrical Student Committee, Bu-Ali Sina University, 2014 Hamedan, Iran Head of Robotic Student Committee, Bu-Ali Sina University, 2014 Hamedan, Iran Bu-Ali Sina University Award as an Exceptionally Talented 2013 student 2013 Coordinator of 1st Conference of Industry Relationship with University, Hamedan, Iran Member of Execution Committee of National Spaghetti 2013 Bridge Contest, Bu-Ali Sina University, Hamedan, Iran (Considered as a Green Competition) 2013 Member of Executive committee of the 2th Bu-Ali Sina Kooshk-Kaghazi Festival Member of Executive committee of the 2th Bu-Ali Sina Save the Eggs Festival

Skills and Expert

• Programming languages:

Python

C/C++

MATLAB

Familiar with C#, HTML, CSS, PHP (Joomla and WordPress CMS)

• Frameworks:

Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Fairly familiar with PyQT

• Microcontroller and Developer Kit skills:

AVR, ARM (LPC and STM)

Raspberry PI, Familiar with Arduino, NVIDIA Jetson Nano

Softwares:

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), EndNote, Latex CodeVision AVR, Keil uvision, Altium Designer

• Simulation tools:

MATLAB, Proteus, Fairly familiar with Hspice, Pspice

• Graphics and video tools:

Camtasia Studio, Edius, Adobe Photoshop

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- **English** TOEFL exam scheduled for November 22
- Farsi (Persian) Native proficiency

Hobbies

- Management books, technology and startups, Taekwondo and Chess, Gym
- More information are available upon request